# SINAN ONALAN

1000 Escalon Ave APT H1062 Sunnyvale, CA 94085 | (650) 3096231 | sinan@onalan.net

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Able to handle any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team leader/player with excellent technical abilities offering 18 years of related experience.

#### **SKILLS**

**Backend**: C#, PHP, Python, Javascript **Frontend**: Html, Css, Javascript, Xml **Mobile**: Swift, React Native, Xamarin(.Net)

Ionic (Cordova+Angular)

Database: Mysql, Mssql, Postgresql, MongoDb

Javascript Library & Frameworks : Nodejs, Express, React, Angular,

Vue.js, Jquery, Mootools, Extjs

Php Frameworks: Laravel, Codeigniter, Zend, Kohana

Pyton Framworks: Django (Flask learning)

Ruby on Rails (Learning)

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### MARCH 2020 -

#### Senior UI Engineer | Autodesk (via Gimmko) | San Francisco, CA

Design, develop, maintain and support Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) frameworks, tools, services and libraries leveraging public cloud infrastructures. Develop self-service capabilities for platform components and transparent platform-level features to address cross-cutting concerns. Practice strong software development principles and best practices: Test-driven development (TDD), CI/CD, code refactoring **Development Stack:** Java Script (Nodejs, React), Web APIs, Redis, Heroku, AWS, Jenkins, Git, CI/CD, OOP, TDD

#### **JUNE 2019 - MARCH 2020**

#### Full Stack Developer | Crea Inc. | Santa Clara, CA

Building SAS Application Architecture. Working on API's, backend and frontend for the applications. Create user stories and issues, plan sprints, and distribute tasks across your software team.

**Development Stack:** Java Script (Nodejs, Angular, React, Vue.js), .Net Core, PHP 7 (Laravel), Mysql, Mssql, PostgreSQL, MongoDb, Redis, Heroku, AWS, Jenkins, Git, CI/CD, OOP

#### **APRIL 2018 - JUNE 2019**

#### CTO & Lead Developer | Dijital Para | Istanbul, Turkey

Maintained agile, responsible organization with sustained revenue growth by monitoring industry forecasts, honing budgets and adjusting marketing strategies. Initiated operational improvements using lean methodologies to drive efficiency and reduce costs. Interviewed, supervised and motivated 10+ staff members to achieve optimal productivity.

Development Stack: Javascript (Nodejs, React), Pyton, PHP 7 (Laravel), ReactNative, Mongodb, Mysql, PostgreSQL, Redis, OOP

## **SEPTEMBER 2009 - MAY 2019**

## CoFounder | Crea Mind | Istanbul, Turkey

Services: Creative Web Design, Enterprise Software, Smart Content Management Systems (SCMS), Reporting Softwares, Data Analysis, Seo Supported and supervised team of 7 professionals. Directed technological improvements, reducing waste and business bottlenecks.

**Development Stack**: PHP(Laravel, Codeigniter), MySQL, Mssql, PostgreSQL, Nodejs, Reactjs, Vue.js ReactNative, Ionic, Redis, Angular, MongoDb, Asp.Net MVC, Mssql, Xamarin, Swift, OOP

## **AUGUST 2011 - JANUARY 2012**

## Lead Software Developer | Jolly Tur | Istanbul, Turkey

Developing high quality software design and architecture, produce and implement functional software solutions. Work with upper management to define software requirements and take the lead on operational and technical projects.

Participate and contribute in the full project life cycle, including gathering requirements, system design, implementation, testing, deployment, and support of applications. Reporting status to Release Management. Responsible for program planning, demo, inspection and adaption, synchronization, release planning and improvement planning. Work with execution team and tracking team to record risks, reports and metrics

## **NOVEMBER 2008 - JUNE 2011**

## Sr. Software Engineer | Istanbul 2010 Europe Capital Of Culture Agency | Istanbul, Turkey

Managing Projects and Leading the team. Mentoring team members. Operate as a fullstack developer and able to be successful. Production release management and support as needed. Reviewed code and corrected errors. Suggested improvements to team and project workflow.

# For more information about my experiences please check

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sinan-onalan/

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science: Statistics (Currently Studying)
YILDIZ TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, ISTANBUL

Advanced Computer Programming: C#, ASP.NET, MSSQL EDUTIME ACADEMY, ISTANBUL

# CERTIFICATIONS

Being Marketing Genius certified by European Schools of Economic Solar Power Systems certified by Katip Çelebi University NeuroFormat™ certified by ReCrea Acedemy.